A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Michael S. Teitelbaum FA682
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Michael S. Teitelbaum
1974-1981
Rockefeller Archive Center
Teitelbaum, Michael S.
Ford Foundation
FA682
1.31 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Scope and Contents
Primarily documents activities related to the Population Association of America (PAA)
Arrangement
As received.
Biographical / Historical
Michael Teitelbaum is a demographer, former foundation executive, and educator. He worked at the Ford Foundation during two different stints of time as a Program Officer in the Population Program.
In between his two stints at the Ford Foundation, Teitelbaum worked as a lecturer on demography at Oxford University. He joined the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation in 1983 as a Program Director after his second time at the Ford Foundation and later became Vice President of the organization. Shortly before leaving the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, Teitelbaum became a Wertheim Fellow at Harvard Law School in 2010.
Teitelbaum earned a B.A. in sociology and biology from Reed College and a D.Phil in demography from Oxford University.
- Population Association of America (PAA) Meetings, 1974 (Box 1)
- PAA -- Public Affairs Committee File #1, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA -- Public Affairs Committee File #2 -- Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA -- Public Affairs Committee File #3 -- Correspondence -- Population Resource Center, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA -- Public Affairs Committee File #3 -- Correspondence -- PAC, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA -- Public Affairs Committee File #3 -- Correspondence -- Public Affairs Committee of the PAA, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA/PRC -- Correspondence/Articles -- Michael S. Teitelbaum Paper Requests (Denver) and Notes, 1980 (Box 1)
- Community Level Action Programs, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA Meetings -- Re: Title X, 1981 (Box 1)
- PAA Meeting -- Title X, Mar 25, 1981 (Box 1)
- PAA/PRC Correspondence -- General, 1981 (Box 1)
- PAA/PRC Correspondence -- Public Affairs Committee MST Chairperson, 1980 (Box 1)
- PAA/PRC Correspondence -- Legislative and Policy Update -- Population Colleagues, 1981 (Box 1)
- PAA/PRC Correspondence -- Population Association of America, 1981 (Box 1)
- Senate Foreign Affairs Committee Testimony, 1981 February 27 (Box 1)
- Sudan Refugee Background, 1979 (Box 1)
- Field Notes, 1980 November 20 (Box 1)
- Notes on Ford Foundation Population Meeting -- Cali, Colombia, 1974 October 14-18 (Box 1)